const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="crk",a=200,i=120,t=[{id:407,question:"Solomon’s wisdom surpassed the wisdom of all the people of the East and all wisdom of Egypt because he",option:{a:"prayed and fasted daily",b:"employed the service of seers",c:"judged difficult cases",d:"got his wisdom from God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:318,question:"According to Amos, God desires knowledge of Him rather than",option:{a:"fervent prayers",b:"dependency on the Law",c:"the multitude of prophecies",d:"burnt offerings"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:158,question:"“Thy glory, O Israel upon thy high places! How are the mighty fallen! Tell it not in the streets of Ashkelon… How  are the mighty fallen in the midst of the battle!” The above dirge was written by David when  ",option:{a:"He killed Goliath  ",b:"Uriah the Hittite died  ",c:"Saul and Jonathan died  ",d:"Abner was killed by Joab"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:509,question:"God fed the Israelites with Manna at the wilderness of",option:{a:"Zin",b:"Elim",c:"Sinai",d:"Sin"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:545,question:"Amos is often referred to as a prophet of",option:{a:"doom",b:"love",c:"hope",d:"justice"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:38,question:"“Bring your necks under the yoke of the king of Babylon and serve him and his people and live” who gave this advice? ",option:{a:"Jeremiah ",b:"Isaiah ",c:"Ezekiel ",d:"Amos"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:958,question:"What was Nehemiah’s immediate reaction to the news concerning Jerusalem? He ",option:{a:"wept.            ",b:"prayed           ",c:"fainted",d:"fasted."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:132,question:"“Talitha cumi”  means  ",option:{a:"Dorcas, Arise",b:"Little girl, I say to you, arise ",c:"Thy will be done",d:"Jesus is coming"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:410,question:"The sins of Israel during the reign of Ahab consisted of",option:{a:"worship of the king",b:"trampling upon the poor",c:"worship of idols",d:"desecrating the Temple"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:485,question:"Peter urged all Christians to endure sufferings in faith conscious of the fact that",option:{a:"Jesus, himself also resisted suffering",b:"the devil could lure them from faith with suffering.",c:"only the physical body is affected.",d:"suffering is temporary and leads to eternal glory."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:585,question:"By saying that no human being will be justified in the sight of God by works: Paul meant that",option:{a:"the mosaic law was useless in ensuring justification for man.",b:"the law had been weakened in human flesh.",c:"knowledge of sin came through the law.",d:"Moses who gave the law was not justified by the law."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:351,question:"God led the Israelites in the wilderness during the day in form of",option:{a:"fire",b:"light",c:"cloud",d:"rainbow."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:10,question:"Manahem, the son of Gadi reigned over Israel for ",option:{a:"eight years ",b:"twenty years ",c:"six month ",d:"ten years."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:257,question:"“...but should write to them to abstain from the pollutions of idols and from unchastity and from what is strangled and from blood...” The statement above was made at the Council of Jerusalem by",option:{a:"Philip",b:"Simon",c:"James",d:"Peter"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:730,question:"St Paul, in 'Law and Grace', although man was condemned, he has been redeemed through the _____",option:{a:"Compliance to the laws of the God",b:"Righteousness of his deeds",c:"Grace of God",d:"Faith in Christ Jesus"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:299,question:"God visited the children of Israel on Mount Sinai during the giving of  the commandments through",option:{a:"a storm",b:"mist and dew",c:"smoke and fire",d:"a still small voice"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:357,question:"In his reform, King Josiah first attacked the",option:{a:"prostitutes that came around the temple at night",b:"priests that made burnt offerings in the temple",c:"Canaanite divinities - the Baal and Ashera",d:"traders who profaned the temple."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:448,question:"In their dealings with God, Abraham and Sarah learnt the 	following lessons except that God is",option:{a:"able to bless the righteous.",b:"faithful to His promise",c:"all powerful-nothing is too hard for Him.",d:"not in a hurry to carry out His promises."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:714,question:".I desire steadfast love and not sacrifice, offerings”. This statement was the central theme of the prophecy of __________.",option:{a:"Elijah",b:"Ezekiel",c:"Hosea",d:"Isaiah"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:1059,question:"Huldah, the prophetess announced evil upon Judah and its inhabitants because people ",option:{a:"had burned incense to other gods ",b:"were marrying foreign women ",c:"were disobedient to the law of God ",d:"had failed to keep the sabbath"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:591,question:"In Philippians, Paul taught that Jesus ‘humility and death on the cross earned Him",option:{a:"salvation for Israel.",b:"adoption as son of God.",c:"exaltation as Lord.",d:"eternal life in the kingdom."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:365,question:"Jesus came to John at River Jordan to",option:{a:"proclaim himself as Messiah",b:"disclose himself to John",c:"call some of John’s disciples",d:"receive baptism like others."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:204,question:"Naboth would not give the vineyard to Ahab because it was",option:{a:"under cultivation",b:"inherited from his father",c:"better than Ahab’s offer",d:"undervalued by the king"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:1016,question:"The incidents that took place following Jesus’ death on the cross did not include the ",option:{a:"tearing into two of the temple’s veil. ",b:"quaking of the earth that broke the rocks. ",c:"the opening of the tombs. ",d:"trembling of the chief priest and his conversion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:880,question:"To which religious party did Gamaliel belong? The",option:{a:"Zealots",b:"Sadducees",c:"Pharisees      ",d:"Herodians"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:1077,question:"The charge of drunkenness was levelled against the apostles on Pentecost day because",option:{a:"they were drunk before nine o’clock ",b:"they spoke in other tongues",c:"a power descended on them ",d:"they made an unintelligible noise"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:741,question:'"I gave you cleanness of teeth in all your cities". By this statement, God gave them ______',option:{a:"New set of teeth",b:"No food to eat",c:"No water to drink",d:"No teeth at all"},section:"",image:"",answer:" b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:292,question:"In addition to the declaration of freedom to the exiles in Babylon, King Cyrus ordered for",option:{a:"free will offering for the house of God in Jerusalem",b:"the release of Jewish, slaves in the empire",c:"security check on the Jews before departure",d:"support from craftsmen in Babylon."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:15,question:"The renowned interpreters of the Mosaic Law in the time of Jesus were the ",option:{a:"Sadducees ",b:"Scribes ",c:"Herodians ",d:"Pharisees"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:1014,question:"“My son your sins are forgiven”. These were the words of  Jesus to the   ",option:{a:"demonia",b:"paralyti    ",c:"man born blind  ",d:"centurion’s servant"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:641,question:"According to Paul in Corinthians, generosity produce",option:{a:"righteousness",b:"salvation",c:"the grace of God",d:"thanksgiving to God"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:862,question:"Nehemiah showed concern for this nation by",option:{a:"reviving Yahweh worship",b:"rebuilding the temple",c:"reconstructing Jerusalem walls",d:"leading exiles home"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:118,question:"What specifically makes Samson a unique prophet of God? ",option:{a:"He was a Nazarene ",b:"He loved honey ",c:"He killed many at his death ",d:"He spoke with power in riddles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:441,question:"When Christians give freely, God will supply",option:{a:"only for those that give",b:"their needs according to His riches in glory",c:"their needs according to the measure they give",d:"their needs day by day."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:963,question:"Jesus taught in parables in order to",option:{a:"make known the secrets of the kingdom",b:"hide the secrets of life from the public.",c:"make His teachings enjoyable.",d:"enable His disciples preach better"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:278,question:"When God called Moses to deliver the Israelites, he resisted because he could not speak and he was told to",option:{a:"perform some signs with his rod",b:"wait for a sign from God",c:"go with Joshua who would speak for him",d:"go with Aaron who would speak for him"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:849,question:"Beside being a true prophetess, Deborah could also be described as a woman of",option:{a:"love",b:"glory",c:"peace",d:"charity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:1011,question:"During the rebuilding of the temple, Zerubbabel rejected the offer of help from the    ",option:{a:"inhabitants of Ammon. ",b:"           people of Samari   ",c:"friends of Sanballat and Tobiah        ",d:"governors of the provinces beyond the rivers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:744,question:'"It shall be neither mine nor yours; divide it" what was to be divided?',option:{a:"Elijah's mantle",b:"Jesus Garment",c:"Live Baby",d:"Solomon's Kingdom"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:55,question:"The lesson, who Jesus teaches in the parable of the Good Samaritan is that your neighbor is ",option:{a:"only your friend ",b:"your next of king ",c:"a distant friend ",d:"anyone who needs your help"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:1010,question:"God’s constant love for unfaithful Israel is demonstrated in the book of ",option:{a:"Amos ",b:"Isaiah ",c:"Hosea ",d:"Ezekiel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:147,question:"During his first missionary journey, Paul first recorded sermon was delivered at  ",option:{a:"Perga   ",b:"Iconium ",c:"Antioch",d:"Lystra "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:1002,question:"On Mount Gilboa, king Saul decided to commit suicide in order to avoid  ",option:{a:"ridicule from the Philistines.",b:"witnessing the death of his sons   ",c:"being killed by his armour-bearer.    ",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:694,question:"According to Paul in Galatians, law ceased to be our custodian as soon as",option:{a:"it was made available to us.",b:"Christ adopted us as his children.",c:"we adopted the faith of Abraham.",d:"we stopped worshipping the elemental spirits."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:79,question:"Those inspired by God to lead the tribes of Israel in battle were the ",option:{a:"Judges  ",b:"Captains of Guard  ",c:"priest  ",d:"prophet  "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:360,question:"The universal nature of God was demonstrated in the salvation of the people of",option:{a:"Joppa",b:"Tarshish",c:"Tekoa",d:"Nineveh."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:228,question:"Herod persecuted the early church because he was",option:{a:"opposed to the Apostles’ teaching",b:"impressed by his growing popularity after killing James",c:"unhappy that the Jewish leaders were not doing enough havoc to the apostles",d:"asserting the extended powers granted him Rome."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:265,question:"In Luke, at the Last Supper, Jesus revealed His",option:{a:"resurrection",b:"imminent sufferings",c:"love for His disciples",d:"ascension."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:905,question:"Your love is like the morning cloud, like the dew that goes early”. What did Hosea mean by this statement? ",option:{a:"Israel’s relationship with God was shortlived ",b:"Israel did not truly love God as she should ",c:"Israel did had love for other gods ",d:"Israel had no love for God"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:466,question:"God spoke through Amos that He would punish Israel for the following sins except that they",option:{a:"sold the righteous for silver.",b:"sold the needy for a pair of shoes.",c:"trampled the head of the poor into the dust.",d:"pursued their brothers with the swords."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:915,question:"Jesus’ call of the first four disciples to catch men rather than fish implies that they were to ",option:{a:"be trained to become Rabbis. ",b:"convert the Jews into Judaism. ",c:"propagate the teachings of Jesus. ",d:"win proselytes back to Jesus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:973,question:"Pilate referred Jesus to Herod for trial because",option:{a:"Pilate and Herod were good friends",b:"Jesus did not cooperate with Pilate.",c:"Jesus lived in the jurisdiction of Herod.",d:"Pilate and Herod were enemies."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:658,question:"David bitterly mourned when Abner was slain by",option:{a:"Ishbosheth.",b:"Absalom.",c:"Asahel.",d:"Joab."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:724,question:"One significance of St Paul's teaching on Resurrection is that__________",option:{a:"Christians must not underestimate the power of baptism by immersion",b:"As Christ rose and ascended into glory, so as also must uphold the observance of law",c:"The foundation of their hope of salvation is in Christ's resurrection",d:"The second coming of Christ is near"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:22,question:"Who is an atheist? ",option:{a:"someone who does believe in God ",b:"someone who rejects completely the idea of a divine being ",c:"someone who believes that it is impossible to know if there is God or not ",d:"someone who abuses religious people."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:58,question:"The prophet who was with the exiles of 597 BC in Babylon was ",option:{a:"Moses ",b:"Hosea ",c:"Micah ",d:"Ezekiel."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:633,question:"Paul informed the Galatians that the gospel he preached came through (Gal. 3:23-29)",option:{a:"a revelation of Jesus Christ",b:"his desire to lead them",c:"inspiration from the angels",d:"the faith of men."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:347,question:"The land, the sea and vegetation were created on the",option:{a:"first day",b:"second day",c:"third day",d:"fifth day."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:396,question:"Paul, unhappy with high incidence of idleness among the Thessalonians, commanded them to",option:{a:"assist those brothers who live in Idleness",b:"exhort the busy-bodies to leave the church",c:"ensure that any one who does not work must not eat",d:"regard the lazy ones as enemies"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:886,question:"James maintained that the double-minded man would not have his prayers answered because he",option:{a:"is unstable in all his ways",b:"asks for things with selfish motives",c:"prays with unforgiving hearts",d:"intercedes with a sinful heart"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:801,question:"Solomon showed lack of wisdom when he ",option:{a:"put up temples for the gods of his wives ",b:"married many wives with children ",c:"invited the Queen of Sheba ",d:"gave out judgement to two harlots."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:89,question:"‘Now I known that Lord has sent his angel to deliver me ……”who said this? ",option:{a:"Joseph ",b:"Moses ",c:"Paul ",d:"Peter "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:548,question:"The wife of Moses was called",option:{a:"Rebecca.",b:"Rachel.",c:"Zipporah.",d:"Deborah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:1088,question:"“Live as free men, yet without using your freedom as pretest for evil” Peter by this text was calling on Christians to",option:{a:"resist the devil always.",b:"do what is right      ",c:"fight for their freedom ",d:"endure pain while suffering"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:68,question:"The meaning of Ephphatha is ",option:{a:"be opened ",b:"be still ",c:"be silent ",d:"little girl, arise"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:435,question:"“It is necessary to circumcise them, and to charge them to keep the law of Moses.” In response to the Pharisees’ statement above, Peter rebuked them, by saying that God has",option:{a:"made circumcision for only those in leadership",b:"chosen the Israelites among other people",c:"cleansed the Gentiles’ heart by faith",d:"put the yoke upon the Gentiles’ necks."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:997,question:"Deborah, a prophetess who was a judge in Israel was the wife of    ",option:{a:"Joshu ",b:"Abijah",c:"Lappidoth.  ",d:"Sisera."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:540,question:"One of the prophets that prophesied hope for Israel in spite of God’s promise of punishment was",option:{a:"Amos",b:"Jeremiah",c:"Obadiah",d:"Hosea"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:1012,question:" “And I asked them concerning the Jews that survived, who has escaped exile, and concerning Jerusalem...” These were   the words of ",option:{a:"Jeremiah. ",b:"  Nehemiah ",c:" Ezr",d:"Hanani"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:995,question:"After the departure of the Israelites God made Pharaoh pursue them in order to ",option:{a:"force Israel to return to Egypt",b:"hasten Israel’s journey through the wilderness. ",c:"make Israel obey Moses. ",d:"get glory over Pharaoh and his host."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:1025,question:"Paul was stoned and dragged out of the city by ",option:{a:"the Lyconians and the Ephesians. ",b:"enemies of the healed lame man. ",c:"Jews from Antioch and Iconium. ",d:"Jews in the Synagogue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:623,question:"The impact of Jesus’ miracle of turning water into wine was that the",option:{a:"servants were astonished",b:"master of ceremony believed",c:"disciples believed more in Him",d:"people glorified God."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:719,question:"Jeremiah prophesied God's punishment of the Israelites because they had_______",option:{a:"Compromised his worship",b:"Committed atrocities with their neighbors' wives",c:"Trampled on the needy",d:"No belief in his message"},section:"",image:"",answer:" a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:30,question:"The two Hebrew midwives instructed by pharaoh to kill the Hebrew male babies at birth were:",option:{a:"Zipporah and Pauh ",b:"Pauh and Miriam ",c:"Shiphrah and Zipporah ",d:"Shiprah and Puah"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:125,question:"True religion, according to Amos’ submission, is the one in which  ",option:{a:"God is always appeased with sacrifices and tithes ",b:"Foods and drinks are served as a mark of love ",c:"Justice and righteousness flows like an endless stream  ",d:"Feast and solemn assemblies play important roles "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:604,question:"The Hebrew midwives who obeyed God rather than Pharaoh were blessed with",option:{a:"favour from all the Israelites",b:"long life in Canaan",c:"resources",d:"families"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:911,question:"According to Matthew’s account of the baptism of Jesus, the voice from heaven said ",option:{a:"“here is my beloved son...” ",b:"“this is my beloved son...” ",c:"“thou art my beloved son...” ",d:"“see my beloved son...”"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:305,question:"God promised Abraham that nations of the earth shall be blessed through him because",option:{a:"he had obeyed Him",b:"his descendants had obeyed Him",c:"of his kindness to Hagar",d:"of  his exemplary leadership."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:260,question:"According to Luke, when Moses and Elijah appeared during the Transfiguration, they spoke of Jesus’",option:{a:"departure",b:"second coming",c:"resurrection",d:"trials."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:178,question:"Who was the secretary employed by Jeremiah to write his prophecy?",option:{a:"Amanuensis  ",b:"Amos  ",c:"Baruch  ",d:"Joshua"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:770,question:'"What you sow does not come to life unless it dies". This was______',option:{a:"the message of St. Paul's teaching on the second coming of Christ",b:"made by St. Paul to Elymas, the magician",c:"the statement of Jesus to Martha",d:"the response St. Paul instructed Christians to give to those who doubt the resurrection of Christ"},section:"",image:"",answer:" d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:791,question:"On the fourth day, God created the sun, moon and stars for the following purposes except  ",option:{a:"to separate the day from the night",b:" for signs of seasons, days and years",c:" to give light upon the earth.     ",d:"to dry up flood from the face of the earth."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:966,question:"According to Luke, the third temptation of Jesus was that He should ",option:{a:"jump down from the high mountain. ",b:"jump from the pinnacle of the temple",c:"bow and worship him",d:"order the stone to become bread."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:88,question:"The proconsul when Paul arrived in commit was called",option:{a:"Festus ",b:"portions ",c:"Pilate ",d:"Gallio "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:765,question:"For how long did the Lord supply the children of Israel with manna in the wilderness?",option:{a:"Forty Years",b:"Thirty-eight years",c:"Eleven months",d:"Twenty two years"},section:"",image:"",answer:" a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:942,question:"Abram’s obligation in his covenant with God was to ",option:{a:"change Sarai’s name to Sarah.",b:"walk before God blamelessly",c:"change his name to Abraham. ",d:"offer his son Isaac as a sacrifice."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:935,question:"According to Paul in second Thessalonians, one of the signs of the second coming would be ",option:{a:"revelation of the man of lawlessness. ",b:"an explosion of world population. ",c:"increasing rate of fake disciples. ",d:"flagrant violation of God’s law"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:172,question:"Render to Caesar the things that they are Caesar’s and to God the things are God’s, the above quotation emphasizes  ",option:{a:"Obedience to divine authority  ",b:"Striking a balance between civil and divine authorities ",c:"Disobedience to civil authority  ",d:"Total rejection of both divine and civil authorities"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:226,question:"Before his ascension, Jesus commissioned his disciples to go to all nations and",option:{a:"cast out demons",b:"heal the sick",c:"raise the dead",d:"make disciples of them"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2005"},{id:771,question:"In the Gospel according to St. Matthew, Jesus sent His disciples to_______",option:{a:"the Gentiles",b:"the Samaritans",c:"the Jews",d:"the Greeks"},section:"",image:"",answer:" c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:463,question:"When Isaiah saw the Lord in His holiness and glory, he exclaimed",option:{a:"“Blessed is me for 1 am truly holy”.",b:"“Woe is me! For I am lost”",c:"“Blessed be the name of the Lord”.",d:"“I am finished, for I have seen a holy God”."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2009"},{id:878,question:"The resurrection stroy encourage Christians to believe that the Lord they adore is",option:{a:"still alive today",b:"a miracle working God",c:"Lord over evils",d:"powerful and Just"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:512,question:"Why did Pilate send Jesus to Herod during the trial?",option:{a:"Jesus, as a Galilean was under Herod’s jurisdiction",b:"Pilate had no power to pass the death sentence",c:"Herod’s court was the last point before crucifixion",d:"Herod had longed to see Jesus perform miracles"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:92,question:"Joshua’s first victory was in ",option:{a:"Ai ",b:"Gibeon ",c:"Jordan ",d:"Giligal "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:388,question:"New life in Christ means",option:{a:"paying your tithe regularly",b:"helping the poor and the needy",c:"being dead to sin",d:"getting baptized."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:631,question:"According to the Gospel of John, Jesus is the true vine while the vinedresser is (John 15:1)",option:{a:"the Holy Spirit",b:"His father",c:"the gardener",d:"His mother"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:61,question:"The king of Persia who made it possible for the return of the exiles form Babylon was ",option:{a:"Dairus ",b:"Cyrus ",c:"Zechariah ",d:"Zerubabel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:671,question:"The incidents that took place following Jesus’ death on the cross did not include the",option:{a:"tearing into two of the temple’s veil.",b:"quaking of the earth that broke the rocks.",c:"the opening of the tombs.",d:"trembling of the chief priest and his conversion."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:90,question:"The seven deacons were appointed by ",option:{a:"conduct a mission to the Gentiles",b:"Replace the twelve ",c:"Lead the church in Jerusalem ",d:"Help in the distribution of food "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:833,question:"According to Peter, a Christian should exercise his freedom by ",option:{a:"doing what is right.         ",b:"claiming his freedom at all cost",c:"enduring pain while suffering. ",d:"using it as a pretext for evil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:308,question:"Saul’s decision to consult a medium displayed his lack of",option:{a:"faith in his army",b:"faith in God",c:"leadership qualities",d:"respect for the dead."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:382,question:"Sin that reigns in our mortal bodies makes us obey",option:{a:"one another",b:"rules and regulations",c:"our passions",d:"our rulers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2008"},{id:974,question:"After the resurrection, the Early Church met to",option:{a:"determine how to deal with the Sanhedrin.",b:"plan the expansion of the church.",c:"appoint a replacement for Judas Iscariot",d:"determine the inclusion of the Gentiles in the church"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:251,question:"In Romans, Paul condemned sin taking over mortal bodies in the new life as instruments of",option:{a:"greediness",b:"wickedness",c:"sadness",d:"foolishness."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:578,question:"When the apostles in Jerusalem heard that Samaria had received the gospel, they sent to them",option:{a:"Mark and Barnabas.",b:"Peter and John.",c:"Paul and John.",d:"Peter and Paul."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"},{id:887,question:`
 Which of the following, accordings to James is an important
 factor for effective prayer?
`,option:{a:"Love",b:"Faith",c:"Hope",d:"Mercy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2012"},{id:523,question:"“How is it that you have agreed together to tempt the spirit of the Lord ....” The statement above was made in reference to the greed of",option:{a:"Gehazi and Naaman",b:"Ahab and Jezebel",c:"Judas and scribes",d:"Ananias and Sapphira"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2015"},{id:1071,question:"The tearing of the temple curtain into two meant ",option:{a:"there was the need for a new curtain",b:"Gentiles would now enter the Holy of Holies ",c:"all men could now worship freely in the Temple ",d:"there was now open access to God"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:665,question:"God’s constant love for unfaithful Israel is demonstrated in the book of",option:{a:"Amos",b:"Isaiah",c:"Hosea",d:"Ezekiel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:303,question:"Why was God angry with Eli?",option:{a:"Eli’s sons disregarded the people’s warning",b:"Eli’s sons were wicked people.",c:"Eli’s sons dishonoured God and he treated them with levity.",d:"Eli’s sons were appointed as priests against God’s will."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:1028,question:"Paul in Romans declared “for as by one man’s disobedience many were made sinners, so by one man’s obedience many  will be made...” ",option:{a:"innocent.                 ",b:"righteous.",c:"faithful.",d:"Christians"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:932,question:"The Philippians showed their solidarity with Paul while in prison by ",option:{a:"using Ephraphroditus to appeal for his release. ",b:"sending gifts to him through Ephaphroditus. ",c:"sending envoys from Corinth to defend him. ",d:"offering regular sacrifices on his behalf"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:940,question:"According to Peter, Christians who suffer for Christ should not be ashamed but should",option:{a:"glorify God.",b:"be encouraged.",c:"be patient.",d:"be grateful."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:1029,question:"Which of the following is not true about spiritual gifts as taught by Paul? ",option:{a:"Gifts should be used with all modesty ",b:"No gift can be independent of others ",c:"Gifts have nothing to do with the level of one’s faith ",d:"Specific gifts perform specific functions"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:170,question:"According to Peter, Judgment of God must first begin in  ",option:{a:"the house of God  ",b:"the public places  ",c:"the midst of criminals ",d:"the government auditoria "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"post-utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:717,question:"God instructed Saul to utterly destroy Amalek because___________",option:{a:"He abhors Idolatory and all forms of Unrighteousness",b:"Its people opposed the Israelites on the way after departing Egypt",c:"Its people encouraged Israel to disobey God",d:"Samuel had prayed for it destruction"},section:"",image:"",answer:" b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2019"},{id:938,question:"According to Peter, doing the right thing is a way of expressing",option:{a:"our rights.",b:"our freedom.",c:"faith in Christ.",d:"dislike for evil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2013"},{id:961,question:"The opposition to the rebuilding of the temple was resolved by ",option:{a:"constant prayer. ",b:"edict issued by Darius",c:"fighting the opponents",d:"Ezra’s dialogue with opponents"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2011"},{id:1050,question:"Saul lied to Samuel when the (Saul)",option:{a:"allowed the soldiers to bring booties of the war home ",b:"said that he had utterly destroyed the Amalekites. ",c:"failed to kill the King of the Amalekites ",d:"spared the Kenites in the war against the Amalekites"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2015"},{id:818,question:"St. John refers to Jesus’ miracles as ‘signs’ because they ",option:{a:"acceptance of Jesus as son of Go ",b:"proofs of the kingdom of Go ",c:"faith in Jesus as the means to eternal life.    ",d:"demand for more wonders"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2010"}],s={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:t};export{t as data,s as default,e as message,a as status,o as subject,i as total};
